logentries.com 2016-04-07

# Privacy Policy | Logentries Log Management

Effective Date: 10-13-2015

This privacy policy describes for users of the Logentries.com website (the “Website”) what information we may collect from users (each, a “Customer”, “You”, “you”, “Your” or “your”) and how we collect, store, and protect such information. Should you have any further questions please do not hesitate to contact us.

**1.WHO WE ARE**

1.1. The Website and the Logentries products and services (the “Service”) are provided by Rapid7 Ireland Limited, an Irish registered private limited company, Registered Company Number 481775 which has its registered office at 111 Delwood Walk, Castleknock, Dublin 15, Ireland (collectively, “we”, “us”, “Logentries”). We can be contacted at the contact points listed on the Website.

**2\. OUR ROLE AS DATA PROCESSORS; INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

2.1. Sign-in Data: The Website allows Customers who are interested in the Service to contact Logentries. If you contact us through the Website, we will collect certain personal data about you when you subscribe to the Service, including your name, organization, email address, payment card details and any additional contact information that you disclose to us (collectively, “Customer Information”).

2.2. Log Data: While using the Service, the Customer may provide log data to us through the Service, for which Customer remains solely and exclusively responsible. To this end, Customer warrants, represents and undertakes to us as follows:

2.2.1. That the log data provided by Customer through the Service will not contain (i) any personal data (within the meaning of Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (“DPA”)), (ii) personal information the disclosure of which is restricted under the United States Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act or other United States statute or regulation, or (iii) any other identifying information that would permit the physical or online contacting of a specific individual, including first and last name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or taxpayer identification number (the identifying information in this clause (iii) collectively, “Third Party Personal Data”); or

2.2.2. Where the log data provided by the Customer contains Third Party Personal Data, the Customer has obtained all necessary consents from all applicable data subjects to enable the Customer to use and transfer such data (including outside of the EEA) in connection with the Service.

2.3. Cookies and Command Lines: Customers interact with the Service by logging in through a browser and using command line access to navigate their account file system, remove and upload logs and to export log data to their local file system. The Service also uses “cookie” technology. A cookie is a little piece of text stored by the browser on your computer, at the request of our server. We may use cookies to collect data related to the usage of the Website and to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your personal preferences so you do not have to re-enter them each time you connect to our website. You are always free to decline our cookies, if your browser permits, or to ask your browser to indicate when a cookie is being sent. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion. Note that if you decline our cookies or ask for notification each time a cookie is being sent, this may affect your ease of use of the Website.

**3\. HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

3.1. . We will use and retain Customer Information in our role as a “data controller” as defined in the DPA solely for the purpose of providing you with the Service as further described in our website and in our Terms of Service contained within the Logentries website. Click here to review the Agreement.

3.2. We may also create statistical, aggregated data relating to our Customers and the Website for analytical purposes. Aggregated data may be derived from Customer Information, log data provided by Customers and/or Third Party Personal Data but in its aggregated form will not identify any individual. This data is used to understand our customer base and to develop, improve and market the Service.

3.3. We may contact you for marketing purposes in line with any consents you have provided to us at the point when you provided us with your Customer Information or subsequently.

3.4 We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

3.5. Our Web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

3.6. Our Website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at support@logentries.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

3.7. From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our sites. If you participate, we may request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information such as your name, company, and email or telephone number, and demographic information such as your title and the size of company you represent. 

We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or personalize the site (in the case of anonymous information collected in surveys), to send participants an email newsletter. 

3.8. Notwithstanding the above, we may use any information we collect to the extent required by law or if in Logentries’ reasonable discretion use is necessary to investigate fraud or any threat to the safety of any individual, to protect Logentries’ legal rights or to protect the rights of third parties.

**4\. WHAT INFORMATION WE DISCLOSE TO THIRD PARTIES**

4.1. In some cases we may engage third party service providers to provide services to us, in which case we shall disclose your Customer Information to such service providers under written agreement that prohibits further disclosure of such information.

4.2. We may disclose aggregated data that does not contain Customer Information or Third Party Personal Data to any third parties, such as potential customers, business partners, advertisers, and funding sources, in order to describe our business and operations.

4.3 We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by contacting [support@logentries.com](mailto:support@logentries.com "Contact Support"). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

Our third party advertising partner may employ a software technology called clear gifs, that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. 

4.4. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we reserve the right to disclose any information we collect in connection with the Website, without further notice to you to any law enforcement or regulatory authority to the extent required by law or if disclosure is necessary, as determined in our reasonable discretion, to investigate fraud or any threat to the safety of any individual, to protect our legal rights or to protect the rights of third parties.

**5\. DATA SECURITY**

5.1. We use commercially reasonable security precautions to protect the security and integrity of your Customer Information in accordance with this policy and applicable law. However, no Internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that security breaches will not occur. Without limitation of the foregoing, we are not responsible for the actions of hackers and other unauthorized third parties that breach our reasonable security procedures.

5.2. If Customer transmits personal data using the Service, the Customer shall comply with its obligations under all applicable law, including as a data controller and data processor under the DPA.

5.3. Logentries hosts and stores data on Amazon Web Services’ cloud platform and on other cloud platforms which will be described in our FAQs from time to time. Accordingly, Customer’s Logentries account data is kept separate from other customers’ data.

5.4. The level of security provided in Amazon’s cloud platform is described in more detail on <http://aws.amazon.com/security/>. Our FAQs also explain the levels of security offered by other cloud providers we may use from time to time.

5.5. If you are not satisfied with the levels of security offered by our cloud providers, you should restrict the nature and amount of personal data or confidential information which you include in your log data.

5.6. Customer may encrypt its data in transit. We ensure the integrity of the Logentries website data by using SSL authentication between the Customer and the cloud, meaning that the cloud must show valid a SSL certificate to each Customer to initiate the link. However, we do not provide any SLAs or warranties on data security, but our approach for handling data storage is published in the FAQ section of our website and the Terms of Service.

**6\. SAFE HARBOR**

6.1. Logentries complies with the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Logentries has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Logentries’ certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

**7\. SALE OF BUSINESS**

7.1. We reserve the right to transfer information, including Customer Information and any Third Party Personal Data, to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of the Privacy Policy.

**8\. UPDATING, VERIFYING AND DELETING PERSONAL DATA**

8.1. You may inform us of any changes in your Personal Data, and in accordance with our obligations under the DPA we will update or delete your Personal Data accordingly. To find out what Personal Data we hold on you or to have your Personal Data updated, amended or removed from our database, please contact [support@Logentries.com](mailto:support@logentries.com "Contact Support"). Notwithstanding any such removal, we may retain copies of such information for archival purposes. Any such data subject requests may be subject to the prescribed fee.

**9\. TESTIMONIALS**

9.1. The Website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. Customer should be aware of this when they leave our site and review the privacy statements of each Web site they visit that collects information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Logentries.

**10\. LINKS**

10.1 The Website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. Customer should be aware of this when they leave our site and review the privacy statements of each Web site they visit that collects information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Logentries.

**11\. CHANGES TO THE WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY**

11.1. We may modify or amend this policy from time to time. If we make any material changes, as determined by us, in the way in which Customer Information is collected, used or transferred, we will notify you of these changes by modification of this Privacy Policy, which will be available for review by you at the Website.

**12\. TERMS OF USE**

12.1 This Privacy Policy forms a part of, and is subject to, the provisions of Logentries’ Terms of Service.

**13\. CONTACT INFORMATION**

13.1. Logentries welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [info@logentries.com](mailto:info@logentries.com)
